New Delhi, India.

E-Mail **Github** 

## Carrier Objective

Highly motivated software engineer with bachelors in Computer Science Engineering having over 5 years of solid industry experience work as a Software Engineer/Full-Stack Developer. Seeking to work with a fast paced startup that provides an interesting and challenging opportunity to capitalize my technical skills in software/web-application designing & Development, data processing & visualization.

#### Work Experience

# 01/2019 - present Full-Stack Web Developer **Upwork Freelancer**

Worked as a fullstack developer/Front-end heavy for multiple projects for over 3 years (with 100% positive client feedback) Some of the core technologies used in these projects were -

- Front-end: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Next.js, Bootstrap
- Backend: Node.Js, Python, Express, Flask
- DB: Mongo, SQL

# 01/2016 - 04/2019 Software Engineer **Goldman Sachs**

- Worked as a part of consumer wealth management team involving in the development and delivery of internal automation tools used by Goldman Associates for managing and tracking consumer disputes.
- Contributed in the design, development and support of adapter layer to connect various back-end services and churn data as per input api requests.
- Extensive worked with high volume/frequency data, data visualization using D3, PDF report generation using JSPDF

## 08/2014 - 11/2016 Software Engineer AirtelxLabs

- Worked on modular UI development for airtel-black using React.js, Redux, Typescript andSASS
- Increased page performance and loading times by implementing code splitting, virtualization, cdn, FE caching and api-throttling.
- > Participated and contributed in agile activities such as sprint grooming, planning, retrospects, tech solutioning discussions.
- Migrated cookie authentication to JSW (json web token) for Kong authentication.
- Delivered an Express based engine to generate and email reporting PDF's to various stakeholders

## Academic Qualification

Qualification	Institute	Year
Bachelors in CSE	Institute of Technology, Delhi India	2014
12 <sup>th</sup> Grade	S.P. Secondary School Srinagar	2010
10 <sup>th</sup> Grade	Burn Hall School Srinagar	2008

## Key Work Projects

#### 1. Airtel Balck

User Acquisition journey and bundling service for airtel-products

Live Link: <a href="https://www.airtel.in/airtel-black/">https://www.airtel.in/airtel-black/</a>

Tech stack: React, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Router, Node.Js/Express, Mongo

#### 2. Single Payer Insurance estimations & comparison

This project is based on a funnel for estimation and comparison of SP Insurance plan along with integrated lead capture. Using Microsoft Graph API's, Flask based back-end is integrated to excel based mathematical model

Live Link: <a href="https://single-payer.herokuapp.com/">https://single-payer.herokuapp.com/</a>

Tech stack: Python/Flask, Microsoft Graph API, React.js

# 3. Fractal Analysis Application

Live Link: https://www.myfractalrange.com/

Tech stack: React, Redux, Node, Mongo

## 4. Financial Application (SPA)

Live Link: <a href="https://www.mxdata.com/order-fulfillment-savings-calculator/">https://www.mxdata.com/order-fulfillment-savings-calculator/</a>

Tech stack: PHP, JS, React.JS, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSpdf, chart.js

### 5. Education Loan search and comparison (Financial Application)

Live Link: <a href="https://moneysmart.sg/education-loan">https://moneysmart.sg/education-loan</a>

Tech stack: JSpdf, Table.js, PHP, Ajax, Bootstrap, WordPress